The third step of the expectation maximization algorithm for
高斯混合模型 (GMM) 期望最大化的算法的第三步
GMM clustering is to take whatever what was produced in step two,
是将第二步计算得到的结果
which is the memberships of all the points to all the clusters,
即所有点对所有聚类的隶属度
the two clusters that we have,
具体来说 我们有两个聚类
and use those to come up with new parameters for the Gaussians.
用这些来为高斯模型提出新的参数
And so, the entire purpose of step three is
所以 第三步的目的在于
to use whatever is step two produced as input,
利用第二步的结果作为输入
and the goal is to fill up this small table,
来填补这个小表格
which is to say for Cluster A,
这是针对聚类 A 的
we need the new mean and a new variance,
我们需要新的均值和方差
and we do the same with Cluster B.
我们对聚类 B 做同样的操作
So, all that it is is just coming up with these four values here.
然后得出这四个值
So, let's go and do that right now.
我们现在开始
And so, the new mean for Cluster A,
基于第二步的结果
given the result of step two,
聚类 A 新的均值
comes from calculating the weighted average of all of these points.
来自于所有这些点的加权平均值
The weighted average does not only account for the parameters of each point,
加权平均值不仅考虑了每个点的参数
but also account for how much it belongs.
还考虑了它隶属度
So it's membership to Cluster A,
因此 这是聚类 A 的隶属度
and that's these terms here.
就是这几项
And so let's calculate that.
我们来对其进行计算
So, this is the table resulting from step two,
这是第二步得到的结果
where we filled up all the memberships for all the points in both clusters.
这里列出了所有点对所有聚类的隶属度
And the numbers are slightly different here because this is
这些数字略有不同
the correct calculation where we accounted for the mixing coefficient.
因为这是考虑了混合系数的正确计算
This value here is just arbitrary.
这个值是任意的
I added it just to showcase that it's not always 99 percent accuracy.
我们添加它只是为了展示它的准确性并不总是99％
It can be 55 and 40 and 30 and anything between zero and one.
它可以是 0 到 1 之间的任何数 比如 55%、40%、30% 等
And so, this is how we calculate the weighted average.
这就是我们计算加权平均值的过程
And it's basically going to each row here and multiplying
它基本上是用这个单元格中的值乘以这一行
this cell by an array or a vector containing these two values,
包含这两个值的数组或向量
and that would be this term.
就是这一项
And then we do that for each row,
然后每一行都进行同样的运算
summing them up and then that would be this entire term.
将它们加起来 得到这一项
And then, we sum up the values of this column,
接着 我们再把这列的值加起来
and that would be what we divide by.
这就是被除数
And then we calculate that,
接着我们进行计算
and we get the you mean for Cluster A.
得到聚类 A 的新 μ
We do the same for a Cluster B, except here,
我们对聚类 B 进行同样的运算 除了这里
we'll be looking at the weighted average of these points here,
我们将使用这些点的加权平均值
and the calculation is almost the same.
其它计算几乎一样
And so, we have the new values.
这样 我们就得到了新值
To calculate the new variance,
要计算新的方差
we do something similar.
我们的方法比较相似
So this term here,
这里的这一项
this looks eerily similar to the regular calculation of how variance is calculated,
看起来与计算方差的常规算式非常相似
except here, we're doing a weighted version of it.
只是我们在这里要做一个加权
So we're multiplying here by the membership to each cluster.
所以我们在这里乘以对每个聚类的隶属度
And so, if we plug in the data that we got from step two,
因此 如果插入我们从第二步得到的数据
we can get a new value for the new variance for Cluster A,
我们可以为聚类 A 的新方差获得一个新值
and we can do the same with Cluster B as well.
我们也可以对聚类 B 做同样的处理
And so now step three is complete.
现在 第三步也完成了
We have the two new Gaussians,
我们有了两个新高斯分布参数
and we can compare them with the old Gaussians.
我们可以把它们与旧的做个比较
Let's look at this graph here.
我们看看这里的图表
So these are the old Gaussians.
这是旧高斯模型
And so, this is an overlay of the old and the new Gaussians.
这是新旧模型的重叠处
And we can see that the green Gaussian started
我们可以看到 绿色的模型
moving to the top and right here a little bit.
略向右上方移动
So this is one step.
这只是一方面
Now, if it doesn't converge,
如果它不收敛
we'll continue to do five, 10, 20,
我们将继续做这样的 5、10、20
30 steps like this until we converge into
30 steps like this 或 30 步
a Gaussian mixture that produces a good result for the problem.
直到其收敛成一个结果不错的高斯混合模型
The fourth step is to evaluate the log-likelihood.
第四步是评估对数似然
And the log-likelihood sums for all clusters here.
这是所有聚类的对数似然和
This is the mixing coefficient related to this cluster,
这是与这个聚类有关的混合系数
and then this is the normal distribution of each point,
这是该聚类的参数下
given the parameter of the cluster,
每个点的正态分布
and this term as a whole is called log-likelihood.
这整个一项称为对数似然
And basically, what this says is that the higher this number is,
基本上 这个数字越高
the more sure we are that the mixer model that we've generated
我们越能确定生成的混合模型可以负责创建数据
is responsible for creating the data or fits the dataset that we have.
或适合我们有的数据集
And so, the purpose here is to maximize this value, this term.
所以 现在的目的是最大化这个值 也就是这一项
We do that by choosing the parameters of the Gaussians,
我们通过选择的参数
including the mixing coefficient,
包括其混合系数 均值及其方差
the mean, and the variance of each Gaussian.
来最大化这个值
The better parameters we pick,
我们选取的参数越好
the higher the value of this entire term will be.
这一项的值也就会越大
And then we do that until the algorithm converges,
然后我们这样做 直到算法收敛
until it reaches a maximum or it starts to increase by a tiny fraction each step.
直到达到最大值 或每一步开始增加一小部分
And so, that's where we can stop the algorithm and say,
这时我们就可以停止运算
"Alright. We have converged.
并完成收敛了
Let's choose those Gaussians as
然后选择那些模型作为高斯混合模型的组成部分
the components of a Gaussian mixture model and that's cluster based on them."
并在它们的基础上聚类
So, this is the final step of
那么这是进行高斯混合模型聚类
the expectation maximization algorithm to do GMM clustering.
期望最大化算法的最后一步
In the next video, we'll look at a visual example,
在下一个视频中 我们将看一个视觉性的例子
where we'll visualize step number one and two and three,
在那里我们将可视化第一、二、三步
the entire process until convergence.
以及直到收敛的整个过程